Have you heard of Misaki?
ミサキって 知ってるか
From the 9th grade, Class 3.
三年三組の ミサキ
Was there anyone named that in Class 3?
三組に そんな人いたっけ
It happened twenty-six years ago.
二十六年前の話な
She'd been popular ever since the 7th grade.
そいつさ
一年の頃から人気者でさ
She was smart, pretty and
had a great personality.
頭も顔も性格もよかったらしいんだ
So, she was loved by students
and teachers alike.
だから生徒にも先生にも好かれててさ
Yeah, there's at least one person
like that in every grade.
いるよねえ 学年に一人はそういう人
But shortly after she started the 9th grade,
ところが三年に上がってすぐ
Misaki died.
そのミサキが死んじゃったのさ
What?
How?
どうして
I heard it was an accident.
事故って聞いた
So, everyone was really shocked.
それでな
みんな ものすごいショックを受けてさ
Until, suddenly, someone said it.
そんな中でふと誰かが言いだしたんだ
Said what?
何って
He pointed to Misaki's desk and said,
ミサキが使ってた机を指さして
"Misaki's right there. She's not dead."
ミサキはそこにいる
ミサキは死んじゃいないって
Was that...
それって
Well, it was just an act.
まあ ふりなんだけどな
But from that day on,
それから三組じゃその後もずっと
Class 3 continued to behave
as though Misaki was still alive.
ミサキは生きてるっていうふりをし続けることにしたのさ
That's kinda creepy.
ちょっと 不気味ね
They kept up the act right up until graduation.
結局 そのふりは卒業まで続いてさ
Do Not Enter
The principal even arranged to have Misaki's
seat included in their graduation ceremony.
卒業式の時は校長の計らいで
ミサキの席が用意されたらしい
Isn't that a good thing?
いい話じゃない
Sure, if it ended there.
ここまでならば
There's more?
続き あるんだ
The rest of the story is...
その続きってのはな
Open the eyelid that conceals the night
夜を覆う　瞼開け
And fear not the evil shadows
もがき影を恐れ怖がれ
I am as a doll
仄暗き棺から
Born from a dusky coffin
産み落とされた人形のように
With a growing body frozen red
体は赤く凍え
And a heart soothed by darkness
心は闇に　あやされ育つ
Can you see me?
君に僕が見えるかい
My nails steeped in fresh blood
繋ぐ手の冷たさに
Sink into the chill of our joined hands
鮮血の爪立てる
Now, let me see you frown
眉寄せてご覧よ
Let us destroy one another
壊し合おう先に続く謎に満ちる結末を
And face the ending full of
mystery that lies ahead
Before we rot away in emptiness
羽も足も　もがれたまま
With our wings and legs ripped away
虚空の中　朽ち果てるように
There is another me
もう一人僕が居て
Who loves someone so much it hurts
誰かを痛いほど愛しているんだ
I wonder, which one is the illusion?
さあ　どっちが幻だろうね
How do you feel? Are you in pain?
どう 苦しくない
はい
No.
My goodness, what a way to start your life here.
本当にもう こっちに来た早々こんな
You poor dear.
可哀想にねえ
Um...
えっと ごめんなさい おばあちゃん
I'm sorry, Grandma.
Oh, no, don't you worry about that.
いやだねえ 気にするんじゃないよお
仕方ないからねえ
You couldn't help it.
Um, does my dad know?
あの お父さんには
I haven't told him.
まだ伝えてないよ
Yousuke is in India at the moment, isn't he?
陽介さん 今ごろはインドかどこかなんでしょう
Want me to tell him?
言っとこうか
I have his number.
携帯の番号を知ってるし
No, thank you, I'll contact him myself.
いえ
あの僕 自分で連絡しますから
Yeah, that's probably best.
うん  その方がいいね
それにしてもねえ
That Yousuke, he's such a dutiful man.
陽介さんも律儀な人だよねえ
In all this time since Ritsuko died...
理津子が死んでもうこんなに経つのに
That's the Yomiyama River flowing
through the center of the town.
街の真ん中を流れてるのが夜見山川ね
And can you see the grounds beyond it?
その向こうにグラウンド見えないかな
Um...
えっと あれですね
You mean that building?
Yes, that's the school you'll be attending.
そう
あれが恒一くんが通う中学校ね
Is that the same school you went to, Reiko?
怜子さんも昔 あの中学に通ってたんですか
そうよ 十四年も前だけどね
Yes, although that was fourteen years ago.
So, my mother went there, too?
じゃあ お母さんも
そう 理津子姉さんも夜見北だった
That's right.
My sister Ritsuko also went to Yomi North.
Yomi North?
夜見北
Yomiyama North Junior High.
夜見山北中学校ね
Oh...
Public schools are a little
different from private schools,
私立と公立の違いはあると思うけど
but it just takes some getting used to.
その辺は慣れよね
恒一くんならすぐ慣れると思うな
I'm sure you'll get used to it in no time.
だといいんですけど
I hope so.
You'll be fine.
大丈夫よ
Once you're out of the hospital,
I'll help you prepare for life at Yomi North.
退院したら 夜見北での心構えを教えてあげるから
Oh, you're reading King this time,
Mister Horror Lover?
今度はキング先生ですか
ホラー少年
じゃあ 後はよろしく
Well, I'll leave you guys alone.
We're students of Yomiyama North
Junior High's 9th grade, Class 3.
僕達 夜見山北中学の三年三組の生徒です
Okay...
はい
I'm Kazami, Tomohiko Kazami.
僕は風見といいます
風見智彦
This is Sakuragi.
こっちは桜木さん
Ah, nice to meet you.
はじめまして 桜木ゆかりです
I'm Yukari Sakuragi.
And this is-
こっちは
Izumi Akazawa.
And this is-
赤沢泉美
Um, did you want something?
あの 何か
Oh, yes.
ええとですね
Sakuragi and I are class officers.
僕と桜木さんはクラス委員長で
Akazawa is in charge of countermeasures.
赤沢さんは対策係で
We came here today as
representatives of Class 3.
今日は三組の代表として来たんです
Countermeasures?
対策係
You just transferred here, right?
転校して来たんでしょう
We heard that you were supposed to
start coming to school on Monday,
えっと 本当は月曜から出てくるはずだったのが
急な病気でって聞いて
but then suddenly got sick.
So, we decided to visit you
on behalf of the entire class.
クラスの代表でお見舞いに行こうって話になったんです
あの これ みんなから
Um, here, these are from all of us.
東京から引っ越して来たんですよね
You moved here from Tokyo, right?
Yeah.
And you went to a private school there?
都内の私立校なんですよね
Why did you transfer?
どうしてなんです
For family reasons.
ちょっと家の事情で
Is this your first time living in Yomiyama?
夜見山に住むのは 初めてですか
Yes.
そうだけど
Oh, I thought maybe you used to live here.
えっと 昔 こっちに住んでたのかなって
I've been here before,
来たことはあるけど
but I've never lived here.
住んだことはないよ
Did you stay for a long time?
長期滞在は
I can't say.
さあ よく覚えてないけど
I don't remember.
I was really young, so... maybe?
ずっと小さい頃なら どうかな
Here.
これを
I made you a copy of all the notes from
the start of the first term.
一学期が始まってからのノートをコピーしてきたから
Thank you!
ありがとう
I think I'll start going to school in early May,
登校はたぶんゴールデンウィーク明けになると思うけど
so I'll see you then.
よろしく
Um, Sakakibara?
あの 榊原くん
Yes?
何
Well...
えっと
榊原…
Sakakibara...
Your first name's Kouichi, right?
恒一くんよね
May we call you Kouichi?
恒一くんって呼んでいい
Oh, sure.
どうぞ
We look forward to getting to know you, Kouichi.
これからもよろしくね
恒一くん
こちらこそ よろしく
Same here, thanks.
Kouichi, are you sure you've never
lived in Yomiyama before?
恒一くん
本当に夜見山に住んだことない
それはないと思うよ
I don't think so.
DAD
Oh, pardon me.
すみません
君って夜見北の生徒
Are you a Yomi North student?
Do you have something to do
on the second basement level?
地下二階に 何か用事が
Yes.
そう
だけど 地下二階って
But the second basement level is...
I have something to deliver.
届けものがあるの
My poor other half...
待ってるから
is waiting for me there.
可哀想な私の半身が そこで
ねえ 君
Hey, wait.
What's your name?
名前は 何ていうの
Mei...
メイ
ミサキ メイ
Mei Misaki.
Mechanical Room - Boiler Room
Morgue
レーちゃん おはよ
Good morning, Rei!
How are you?
元気
Good morning!
おはよ
おう おはよう 元気か
Hey there, good morning!
How're you doing?
Morning...
おはよう
It's 2 A.M. over here.
こっちは夜中の二時だ
India sure is hot!
暑いぞインドは
What's up?
どうしたの
You're about to leave for school, aren't you?
今日はこれから学校なんだろう
This is your go-get-'em call.
Be grateful!
激励の電話だ 感謝しろ
Uh, sure.
Feeling okay?
体調はどうだ
How have things been since you
got out of the hospital?
退院してから…
聞こえるか 恒一
Can you hear me, Kouichi?
ちょっと待って 電波が悪いみたい
Hold on, the signal here is bad.
Can you hear me, Kouichi?
I wanted to say-
体調は良好だよ
I'm feeling fine.
心配いらないから
You don't have to worry.
気胸のことはあまり気に病むなよ
Yeah, a collapsed lung's not
the end of the world.
私も若い頃にやったことがある
I had one, when I was a boy.
Really? I didn't know that.
初めて聞いたよ
I never told you.
言いそびれたんだよ
血筋かとか言われたくなかったんでな
I didn't want anyone telling you it's hereditary.
Is it?
血筋か
I actually had it twice, but never again after that.
私も二回やったが その後は一度も発症してない
血筋なら これで打ち止めだ
So if it's hereditary, you're all done.
I hope so.
だといいんだけどね
Think of it as something that's in the past,
まあ 再発はないものと思って
肩肘張らずに適当に頑張れ
and go enjoy your life.
I won't stress over it.
気楽にやるよ
That's my boy!
お義父さんとお義母さんによろしくな
Say hello to your grandparents for me!
暑いぞインドは
Man, India is seriously hot!
おはよ レーちゃん
Good morning, Rei!
Good morning!
おはよ
Rei is your name, you know.
レーちゃんはお前の名前だろうが
Cheer! Cheer up!
元気 元気出してね
Sure, thanks.
うんうん ありがとう
Moving along...
じゃあ 次
夜見北での心構え その三は
The third thing you need to know to
prepare yourself for Yomi North is:
クラスの決めごとは絶対に守ること
Always uphold the class rules.
Okay.
はい
Things might be different in Tokyo,
東京の学校とはちょっと違うと思うんだけど
but here the group matters
more than the individual.
個人よりも集団としてどうあるかが問題なの
I think I can handle that.
それは大丈夫だと思いますよ
Good.
Now, the fourth thing you need to know is-
じゃあ 夜見北での心構え その四は…
Kouichi!
Now, the fourth thing you need to know is-
恒一ちゃん
Breakfast is ready!
ご飯だよお
Breakfast, she says, Kouichi.
ご飯だとさ 恒一
Good morning, Grandpa.
おはよう お爺ちゃん
Good morning.
おはよう
Are you going back to the hospital today?
恒一は今日も病院かね
No, I've been discharged.
もう退院したってば
I start school today.
今日から学校だよ
Ah, school.
おお 学校か
恒一も もう中学生か
You're already in junior high, eh?
Yes, yes.
そうか そうか
I'm glad you're feeling up to it.
元気は何よりだな
I'm in the 9th grade now.
中三だよ
I'll be in high school next year.
来年は高校
If only that hadn't happened to Ritsuko...
理津子もな あんなことにならなかったらな
恒一ちゃん ご飯だよ
Kouichi, breakfast!
Coming!
はい
Why, Rei? Why?
Coming!
どうして レーちゃん
どうして
I hope you'll be able to get along with everyone.
とにかく 皆と仲良くしてください
If you have any troubles at all,
もしも何か困るようなことがあれば
please don't hesitate to talk to me.
遠慮なく相談してくださいね
You can also talk to Ms. Mikami,
the assistant homeroom teacher, of course.
私なり 副担任の三神先生にでも もちろん
Yes, sir, thank you.
はい よろしくお願いします
We look forward to having you with us.
こちらこそ よろしくね
May 6 (Wed.)
Kouichi Sakakibara
I moved here because of my father's job.
父の仕事の関係で こちらにやって来ました
I'm living with my grandparents.
今は祖父母のところに住んでいます
And, um, it's nice to meet you.
ええと あの どうぞよろしく
三組の新しい仲間として 仲良くやっていきましょう
Please give our new friend
a warm welcome, class.
Help each other and work
your hardest together,
お互い助け合い 皆一緒に頑張って
来年の三月には
so that you can all graduate in
prime health next March.
皆一緒に健やかに卒業できるように
Sakakibara, you can take that seat there.
では 榊原くんはあそこの席に
Yes, sir.
はい
病気はもう大丈夫なのかな
Are you all healed up?
Yes, I feel much better.
うん もうすっかり
How does this town compare to Tokyo?
東京とこっちではどうかな
It's not that different.
そんなに変わらないよ
But Tokyo sounds so great!
でもさ いいよね 東京
Small country towns like Yomiyama
have nothing going for them these days.
夜見山みたいな田舎町って 最近益々パッとしないしさ
That's for sure.
だよな 面白いこともねえしな
Nothing interesting happens here.
あっちはあっちで嫌なことあるよ
Tokyo has its downside, too.
It's so noisy, you can't relax.
町はざわざわしてて 落ち着かないし
I guess it might seem that way,
if you've lived there.
住んでたらそういうものかもしれんな
そうかな
You think so?
I'd love to try living in Tokyo!
東京暮らしとかしてみたいな
こっちのほうがずっと静かでいいんじゃないかな
I like it better here; it's much quieter.
And you're surrounded by nature.
自然も多いしね
That's an opinion you'd only hear
from someone who lived in Tokyo.
東京に住んでたものならではの意見だね
I heard your dad is a college professor.
お父さんが大学教授なんだってね
And he's researching in a foreign country now?
それで どこか外国に研究に行ってるって
How did you know that?
何でそれ知ってるの
Everyone knows.
皆知ってるよ
Mr. Kubodera told us.
久保寺先生が言ってたからね
そっか 前の中学のことも
Oh, he did? And about my old school, too?
Pretty much everyone knows.
大体の人は知ってますよ
Ms. Mikami talked to us, too.
三神先生から聞きましたから
I see.
そうだったんだ
It's too bad Ms. Mikami isn't
our homeroom teacher.
どうせだったら 三神先生が担任ならよかったのになあ
She's hot, and she's got killer style, yeah?
美人だし きりっとしてるし な
Well, um...
Oh? Pretty women not your type, Kouichi?
おやおや 恒一ちゃんはきれいなお姉さんはお好みではないのね
It's not that.
そんなわけじゃないけど
Then what kind of girl do you like, Sakakibara?
じゃ 榊原くんはどういうタイプが好きなんですか
Why are you asking me this...
勘弁してよ
By the way, what country is your dad in now?
そういや お父さんが外国って どこに行ってるの
India.
インドだよ
この春から一年ぐらいから
He's been there about a year this spring.
Wow, India, huh?
へえ インドか また熱そうなとこへ
I bet it's hot there.
I wouldn't be able to take it; I can't stand heat.
俺は熱いの苦手だから 無理だな
Consider yourself lucky, Teshy.
喜べてっし お前さんじゃどう頑張っても研究でインド何か行けんぞな
No matter how hard you try, you're never
gonna do research in a place like India.
Yeah, yeah, I'm well aware!
へい へい 行けませんよ
What's wrong?
どうしたの 何か不安なことでもあるの
Is something bothering you?
No, nothing.
いや 別に
But I was wondering about the
other girl who visited me.
そういや お見舞いに来てくれた赤沢さんだっけ
Akazawa, was it?
Is she absent today?
今日はお休み
Yeah, looks like it.
まあ 今日はお休みみたいだよ
Hey! Why don't we give you a tour
of the school during lunch?
じゃさあ 昼休みにでもざっと校内を案内してやろっか
It's tough not knowing where stuff is, right?
知らないとやっぱ不便だろう
Yeah, that's a good idea.
そうだね そうしよう
Thanks.
ありがとう
I appreciate it.
じゃ ぜひ
はい
Ready!
You look like you want to run.
走りたいみたいだね
Yeah, I love running.
うん 走るのは好きだから
Yeah?
そっか
So, you've run before.
君は走ったことがあるんだよね
Um, yeah.
I hear you have a heart condition.
高林くんは 心臓がよくないんだっけ
Yeah, I was born with it,
生まれた時からね
so I don't know what it feels like to run.
走るってどういう感じなのか分からないんだ
I wish I could run with all my strength.
僕も思いっ切り走ってみたいな
You might be able to someday.
いつか できるんじゃないかな
Yeah, maybe you're right.
うん そうだね
Someday.
いつかできるよね
I'm gonna...
ちょっと 保健室で横になって来るよ
go to the nurse's office to lie down.
Are you okay?
大丈夫
It happens all the time.
Are you okay?
いつものことさ
I can get there by myself.
一人で行けるから
榊原くん 高林くんは
Sakakibara?
Where did Takabayashi go?
To rest in the nurse's office.
保健室で休んでくるって
そう
Oh...
I fell yesterday and sprained my ankle.
昨日転んで足を挫いちゃって
So, we don't share P.E. with
another class here?
そういやさ 体育って 二クラス合同でやらないの
Only Class 3 is different.
三組だけ違うんです
Classes 1 and 2, and Classes 4 and 5,
have P.E. together.
一組と二組 四組と五組は合同ですけど
You walked around with Kazami, Teshigawara
and the others during lunch, right?
昼休み 風見くんや勅使河原くんと一緒にいましたよね
Yeah.
Did they say anything to you?
何かその
聞きました
They just gave me a tour of the school.
校内の案内してもらったけど
That's all?
それだけ
Yeah.
That's all?
I see...
そっか
If we're not careful, Akazawa will yell at us.
ちゃんとしないと 赤沢さんに叱られちゃう
Hey, Sakuragi?
あのさ 桜木さん
Yes?
はい
I've been wondering...
ええと ほら
Where's Misaki?
ミサキさんは
Who?
The girl named Mei Misaki.
ミサキメイっていう女の子
The one wearing an eyepatch on her left eye.
ほら 左目に眼帯をした
What?
I didn't see her in the classroom at lunch.
昼休みも教室にいなかったし
榊原くん
Sakakibara?
Hey, Misaki.
ねえ 君 ミサキさん
You watching the P.E. class, too?
体育 君も見学なんだね
Should you be up here?
いいのかな こんなところにいて
I don't know.
さあ
But there's no point in watching from up close.
近くでみていても意味はないから
そういうあなたは大丈夫なの
And you? Should you be up here?
I don't know.
さあ
Were you drawing something?
絵描いてたの
メイって
How do you write "Mei"?
どんな字を書くの
With the character that means "sing."
鳴くっていう字
The same character used in
"sympathy" and "scream."
共鳴の鳴
悲鳴の鳴
I see.
そっか
ええとね
So, do you remember meeting me
at Yomiyama Hospital the other day?
この間夜見山病院で僕と会ったのを覚えてる
In the elevator.
エレベーターでさあ
You got off at the second basement level.
君は地下二階に降りて
Did something like that happen?
あったかも そんなこと
What did you go to the second
basement level for?
あの時 地下二階に何しに行ったの
You said you had something to deliver.
届け物って言ってたよね
You were holding some kind of white doll.
白い人形みたいな物持ってたけど
Is that what you had to deliver-
あれが届け物
I hate being questioned.
Is that what you had to deliver-
そういう質問攻め 嫌い
Oh, sorry.
あ ごめん
I wasn't trying to force you to tell me.
無理に聞こうってつもりじゃないし
ただ その
I just, well...
Something very sad happened that day.
あの日はね
悲しいことがあったから
You are Kouichi Sakakibara, correct?
あなたは榊原恒一
間違いない
Yes.
Your classmates haven't told you?
クラスの皆から何も言われない
Told me what?
何を
They associate your name with death.
あなたの名前は死を連想させるから
But not just any death.
しかも ただの死じゃない
A cruel, irrational death that
took place at this school.
学校が舞台の
残酷で理不尽な死
This school is in a place close to death,
この学校はね
中でも三年三組は
especially the 9th grade's Class 3.
死に近いところにあるの
It's much, much closer to it
than any of the other classes.
他のどのクラスよりも ずっと
死に 近い
To... death?
You really don't know anything, Sakakibara?
何も知らないのか
榊原くん
何も知らないのね
Nothing at all?
Nobody has told you?
誰からも聞いてないんだ
何を
About what?
You'll find out soon enough.
そのうち分かってくるから
You shouldn't try to get close to me.
私には近寄らないほうがいい
You shouldn't talk to me anymore, either.
話すのも もうやめたほうがいい
Why?
何で
You'll find out soon enough.
そのうち分かってくるから
そんな
But...
Goodbye, Sa-ka-ki-ba-ra.
じゃあね サ カ キ バ ラくん
クラスの皆とはうまくやっていけそうかい
Are you getting along with your classmates?
Yeah, I guess.
まあ たぶん
どうかしたのかい
Is something wrong?
No, nothing.
別に 何でも
色褪せてく フィルムのように
Like film that loses its color with time
確かな今も いずれ霞んで
The now that we know will one day fade
何でもなく 笑いあった
That fleeting moment's light
刹那の時間と光
When we shared a laugh over nothing
繋がってゆく 記憶の底に
It now lies, waiting to be found, at the depths
誰かが見つけるためあると信じてる 今でも
Of memories that connect one to the next
This I still believe
"Blueprint"